# **Andrew A Hamlin**

aahamlin@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewahamlin | 860-810-6538

#### **Profile**

A software development manager and servant leader who has delivered industry-leading software solutions recognized by Gartner and KLAS. Over 20 years hands-on experience with Agile software development and release management (Scrum/Kanban), enterprise architecture, cloud architecture, test-driven development, systems integration, CI/CD, global workforce management, and team building.

Earned an *Employee Recognition Award* for transforming Sustaining Engineering operations at Caradigm, quantified by KPIs and performance against SLAs.

#### Relevant Skills

- Nurturing highly engaged software teams embodying trust and transparency
- Innovation and continuous improvement of software delivery processes
- Managing end-to-end product delivery across SDLC (Scrum/Kanban/SAFe)
- Communication to executive levels incl. project plans, budgets, and reports

# Experience

Gerber Technology, LLC: Tolland, CT

2018-2019

# Sr Software Development Manager

Assessed overall release management and development processes and created improved workflows tailored to the organization's needs. Trained 50-person team of developers, QA, & product management Lean/Agile/Scrum methodologies while transitioning from 1-yr to 3-mo release cycles. Led estimation, planning, and delivery for 3 project teams, approx. 30 persons. Initiated data-driven improvements, applying Lean & SixSigma tactics, yielding 86% fewer defects over 2 major releases. Managed 8 direct reports, 20 on/offshore resources, mentored 2 team leads. Onboarded (via acquisition) a 12-person development team. Implemented Jenkins CI server. Led design and transition from SVN to Git SCM.

Sailpoint Technologies: Austin, TX

2017-2018

#### Software Development Manager

Championed and expanded best practices in code reviews, test coverage, documentation, threat modeling, CI/CD, and localization. Led delivery of frontend and backend features in Java, SQL, Angular.js. Served as scrum master of two 6-8 person scrum teams. Managed 8 direct reports. Conducted and facilitated interviews, hiring and onboarding of 4 new hires.

Caradigm USA, LLC: Bellevue, WA (Remote)

2012-2016

## Software Development Manager & Team Lead: 2013 - 2016

Delivered two new products from inception to launch using Agile/Scrum, worked collaboratively with product owners and two 6-8 person scrum teams. Designed and led development of CI/CD pipeline using TFS/MTM/HyperV with gated-checkins and end-to-end test automation, coached team members on its adoption and use. Developed interviewing and onboarding standards and documentation. Personally implemented UI, CLI, REST APIs in C#, SQL, Javascript, Python, and C.

### Sustaining Engineering Manager: 2012 - 2013

Established and owned service level agreements (SLAs) and prioritization of requests from multiple stakeholders incl. customer support, professional services and pre-sales teams. Earned *Employee Recognition Award* for raising customer satisfaction scores (measured by KLAS Research). Managed 10-person on/offshore team. Established and maintained KPIs, dashboards and executive reports to CTO.

Microsoft Corporation: Redmond, WA (Remote) 2010-2012

#### Software Development Engineer II

Defined architecture and led 6-person team transforming a monolithic Java app to service-based architecture in C#/.NET, WCF, WPF, and PowerShell. Co-developed self-contained polyglot build system including static code analysis and test coverage; used by 40+ developers.

Sentillion, Inc: Andover, MA 1999-2010

## Senior Software Engineer

Developed Java and Perl/CGI components for enterprise IAM/SSO solution for Linux and Windows exceeding 99.999% uptime; a *KLAS Top 20 product*. Provided innovative OSS solutions that reduced licensing and fulfillment costs per unit.

#### Personal & Volunteer Activities

Unplugg Enterprises: Easthampton, MA

2019

Prototyped mobile app (iOS/Android): Java, Swift, Dart/Flutter, Adobe XD.

The Master's School: West Simsbury, CT

2014-2015

Created programming elective for students. Taught 16 high school students.

#### Education

Daniel Webster College: Nashua, NH

BS Management and Information Technology